## **GURDEEP SINGH**

■ Christchurch, Broomfield 8042 ■ 0221547375 ■ gurdeepnz19@gmail.com ■ **WWW:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/gurdeep-singhnz/ ■

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A professional with 5+ years of experience as a Web Developer specializing in web-based applications with good eCommerce knowledge. Currently, studying Master of IT Project Management from Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand. For the last five years I have been contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction. Strong experience developing customer-focused websites using different technologies such as Shopify, PHP, React, HTML, CSS, AJAX, jQuery, JavaScript, RESTful APIs. Also, knowledge of AWS and version control systems such as git. Currently, looking for new opportunities to deepen my understanding and expertise in web development. Experienced Developer with 5+ years of experience in creating programs based on specific requirements. Adaptable, diligent and knowledgeable in PHP and Shopify.

#### **SKILLS**

- Apple OS
- Linux
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- Ajax
- JQueru
- Liquid

- Bootstrap
- XML
- PHP
- React
- Trello
- Slack
- Photoshop
- Figma

# WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- https://www.hotmilklingerie.co.nz/
- https://www.diorhomedecor.com/
- https://sundayritual.shop/
- https://shop-audiofusion.com/
- https://www.dailyrobust.com
- https://irtholfashions.com/

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### **SHOPIFY DEVELOPER** 02/2020 to 12/2022

#### **SUFFESCOM SOLUTIONS PVT LTD**

- Designed, developed, and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.
- Tested programs and databases to identify issues and make necessary modifications.
- Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best practices.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.

- Participated in software field testing to verify performance of developed projects.
- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.

#### **WEB DEVELOPER** 09/2018 to 02/2020

#### **STARK EDGE**

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX, and JSON coding.
- Provided front-end website development using Shopify, WordPress, and other editing software.
- Adhered to SEO best practices while designing sites.
- Validated third-party code to comply with internal standards and technical requirements.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS for integration and crossbrowser compatibility.
- Engaged with clients to plan and optimize site issues and queries.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve user problems.

#### **PHP DEVELOPER** 12/2017 to 09/2018

#### **VTAURUS TECHNOLOGIES**

- Wrote server-side and client-side code for server-side projects using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Planned, coded and deployed web-based applications using PHP, MySQL and JavaScript.
- Modified and tested existing MySQL database schemas.
- Regularly updated knowledge of latest industry trends in web development and related technologies.
- Built and maintained internal tools to streamline software development process and enhance productivity.
- Configured and deployed existing and future REST APIs, integrating with third-party APIs.

#### **TESTING INTERNSHIP** 08/2017 to 11/2017

#### **ALLGO EMBEDDED SYSTEMS PVT LTD**

- Completed automation of functional and regression testing.
- Met with quality assurance, developers and project managers to assess scope and sequence of project.
- Created successful test scripts to manage automated feature testing,
- Planned and devised cohesive test plans for projects using advanced testing technologies.
- Optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of IT Project Management, 11/2023

#### Auckland University of Technology - Auckland, New Zealand

• The Impact of Remote Work on Agile Team Performance, How the shift to remote work shapes and influences the performance dynamics of Agile teams - Research Project

Studied: Agile Information Technology Project Management, Cloud Computing,
 Information Technology Project Portfolios in Organizations, Team Facilitation for
 Information Technology Projects, Digital Transformation and Change Management

Master of Science: Information Technology, 05/2017

#### Punjabi University Patiala - Patiala, India

Studied: Introduction to Information Technology, Computer Programming using C,
 Computer Organization and Architecture, Mathematical Foundation of Computer Science,
 Operating Systems, Object Oriented Programming Using C++, Data and File Structures,
 Visual Basic, RDBMS and Oracle

#### PERSONALITY TRAITS

- Effective Communication
- Leadership
- Listening
- Time Management
- Team Building
- Positive Attitude
- Multitasking
- Problem Solving Ability

**AVAILABILITY** 

**Immediately** 

**LICENSE** 

**Shopify Expert** 

**REFERENCES** 

References can be provided upon request.